字幕：Hongjiang399  微信：Hongjiang399
Java编程语言有很长的历史
The Java programming language has a long history.
1991年，Sun微系统公司开始了名为“The Green Project”项目
It started in 1991 when Sun Microsystems began something called The Green Project.
这个项目的目标是创建一门新的可移植编程语言
The goal of The Green Project was to create a new portable programming language,
新语言用于创建可在多种操作系统上运行的应用软件
one that could be used to create applications that could be run on multiple
而不需要重新编译或移植代码
operating systems without having to recompile or port the code.
这门语言最初的名字为"Oak(橡树)",因为当时有一颗橡树
The original name of the language was Oak, for a large oak tree that stood
正好在发明者办公室的窗口外
outside the windows of the developers' offices.
但在项目开始至新语言被发布的这段时间内
But between the time the project began and the time the language was released,
它被重新命名为Java，因为这是当时开发者们很常喝的
it was renamed as Java supposedly because of the amount of coffee that the
一种咖啡
developers were drinking.
Java的首次发布是在1995年，从那之后Java经历了快速
Java was first released to the public in 1995 and thereafter saw a rapid
的改革和变化
evolution and change.
从1995年开始，“一次编写，随处运行”变得流行起来
Starting in 1995 the phrase Write Once, Run Anywhere was popularized.
也就是说，Java的目标就是实现你只需写一次源代码，你只需
Again the goal of Java was that you'd be able to write a program, you'd be able
编译一次而可以运行在Unix，Windows,Mac等
to compile it once and then run it on UNIX, on Windows, on Mac, and other
多种操作系统，只要有一个Java虚拟机环境即可
operating systems for which there was a Java virtual machine.
Java飞速发展
Java evolved swiftly.
最早几年每年都有一个新版本发布
In the early years there was a new release about once a year.
到1996年，Sun发布了第一个完整的Java开发工具(JDK)，并支持
In 1996, Sun released the first complete Java Developers Kit or JDK supporting a
一大堆应用开发任务类型，版本号1.1,接下来一年
broad range of application development tasks, version 1.1, the following year
的改进主要在Java的面向对象属性上，包括内部类和
saw improvements to the object- oriented nature of Java with Inner classes and
JavaBeans，JDBC应用接口(用于数据库交流), RMI(远程方法调用)
JavaBeans, the JDBC API for talking to databases, RMI or Remote Method
RMI运用于分布式系统，还有反射机制(用于改进Java的)
Invocation for distributed systems, and Reflection for improving the dynamic
(动态特性)
capabilities of the language.
到1998年，Java重塑品牌为J2SE，即Java第二个标准版本
In 1998, Java was rebranded as J2SE or Java 2 Standard Edition.
标准版本是跟企业版本区分开来的，企业版本是
The Standard Edition distinguished it from Enterprise Edition which was the
打造大型网页应用的开发框架
framework for building large scale Web applications.
版本号是Java 2，也就是Java 1.2
The version number was Java 2, version 1.2.
显得有点混乱，“J”后面的数字“2”存在了很多年
A little confusing, and the 2 after the J stuck around for many, many years, but
但版本的递增却用小数点后面数字表现
the versions were incremented using point numbers.
Java2SE 1.2 包含了swing图形API接口，用于创建桌面应用
Java2SE 1.2 included the swing graphical API for building Desktop applications,
collections(集合类)框架用于管理多种数据元素，还有一些新工具
the collections framework for managing multiple data elements, and new tools
包括即时编译器和Java插件，插件用于标准化
including the Just-In-Time compiler and the Java Plug-in which standardized the
Java和网页浏览器的交叉版本
version of Java across Web browsers.
两三年后J2SE 1.3版本新增了开发工具，有HotSpot虚拟机
A couple of years later J2SE 1.3 added new tools including the HotSpot JVM,
这是一个新版本的Java虚拟机，还有Java声音API接口和一些漏洞修补
a new version of the Java Virtual machine, the Java Sound API and improved debugging.
2002年的版本1.4新增了一些开发工具，到了2004年，一个主要的
In 2002 version 1.4 added new tools in the language, and then in 2004, a major
更新版本发布了，即J2SE 5.0
new release came out J2SE 5.0.
这个新版本的版本号是1.5,也是5.0
This version was known both as 1.5 and 5.0.
但后面所有新版本的发布都只采用了主版本号递增
But subsequent new releases would just use the major numbers.
也就是后来变成5.0, 6.0, 7.0...
So it'd become 5.0, 6.0, 7.0 and so on.
J2SE 5.0是Java语言的一次重大改进，其中一项新特性叫Generics
J2SE 5.0 was a major new change for the language, a new feature called Generics
其作用是让你能运用强集合性元素数据类型
was implemented that lets you strongly data type collection elements.
还改进了枚举类、可变参数、以及for-each循环结构
Enumerations, variable arguments, and looping with for-each were all improved.
从语言的语法上看，那是最后一次Java语言的重大改进
And in terms of language syntax this was really the last major change to the language.
从那以后Java的改进都属于边角修复
Everything since then has been nibbling around the edges.
到2006年，Java 6.0发布
In 2006 Java 6.0 came out.
改进了数据库连接性能、图形化编程
It improved performance for database connectivity, improved graphical
以及增加其他一些小的特性
programming and added other small features to the language.
后来改进的脚步减缓了，从2006年到2010年Sun微系统发布的
And then the pace of change slowed, from 2006 to 2010 Sun Microsystems released
都属于临时的维护版本
occasional maintenance releases to the language.
你会看到Java 6.0的维护版本如10, 11, 12...
So you'd have Java 6.0 Maintenance Release 10, 11, 12, and so on.
到本课程为止，Java 6.0的维护版本29是最新的
And as of this recording Java 6.0 Maintenance Release 29 is the most recent
一个Java 6.0版本
version of that version of Java.
到了2010年，一个大事件发生了：甲骨文收购了Sun
Then in 2010 a major event occurred. Oracle bought Sun.
Sun微系统品牌以及所有资产，包括Java编程语言
Sun Microsystems and all of its assets including the Java programming language
都编程了甲骨文的一部分
became a part of Oracle.
到本课程的录制为止，甲骨文集团正维护运营着Java语言
And as of the time of this recording Oracle Corporation manages Java along with
以及JCP，即Sun创始的Java社区流程
JCP, the Java Community Process that Sun began.
到2011年J2SE 7发布了
In 2011 J2SE 7 was released.
其中包含了一些如列表所示的小改进，以及增加其他一些小工具
It included minor changes in the language listed here and some other small scale tools.
我们将会看到新版本的Java在未来发布，很可能会被命名
And we are expecting another version of Java down the road, possibly known as
J2SE 8.0，其中将会包含一些跟7.0版本不一样的地方
J2SE 8.0 and it would include many things that were deferred from the version
例如包含一种叫Lambda表达式或闭包
7.0 effort including something called Lambda expressions or closures.
如果你不了解这些，不必担心，现在这些都还不是
If you don't know what those are, don't worry about it, they are not currently a
Java语言的一部分
part of the Java language.
总之，这就是Java语言的全部历史
So that's what's happened in the world of Java since it began.
自1995年以来Java就是一个强大的存在，被用在很多
Java has been around in strength since 1995 and it's been used in a lot of
编程环境中，我将会介绍其中一些编程环境
programming environments, and I'll talk about some of those programming
请见下一视频
environments in the next video.
字幕GitHub: https://github.com/Hongjiang399/JavaEssentialTrainingSRT.git